Cool.
好的
So today, we're going to be talking about software engineering.
今天我们来聊聊软件工程
We're going to be specifically talking about industrial applications of software engineering.
我们将着重讨论软件工程在工业中的应用
Sounds a little fancy.
听起来有点高大上
I promise it's not that fancy.
我保证没那么高大上
We'll be going over some real examples.
我们会讲一些实际的例子
Hopefully, it's a fun lecture just before the midterm starts.
希望在期中考试开始之前 这节课能带给大家一些乐趣
So we're going to talk about a few things today.
所以今天我们要讲一些内容
I realize the gray is not very visible with this projector, but we're going to start out with a background, just what are we talking about in general.
我知道灰色用这个投影仪不太看得清 但我们先从背景开始 也就是我们一般要讨论什么
Then we're going to talk about what code complexity looks like, some frameworks that we can use to address code complexity, some real-life examples of applying these concepts,
我们将讨论代码复杂性的样子、可以用来解决代码复杂性的一些框架、应用这些概念的一些实际例子
最后做一个总结 以结束这节课并获得一些关键的收获
and then finally a summary just to wrap up the lecture and get some key takeaways.
So to start with, that's my ed profile picture.
首先 这是我的ED个人资料图片
You might see me every once in a while.
你可能偶尔会看到我
I'll respond to a question about an exam level discussion.
我会回复一些关于考试水平讨论的问题
My name is Anirudh.
我叫阿尼鲁德
I'm a senior.
我是一名大四学生
I major in EECS and business.
我的专业是EECS和商业
I'm a TA for 61B, as Justin introduced me as.
正如贾斯汀介绍的那样 我是61B的助教
I first taught back in summer 2021, which I realize is probably a long time ago for a lot of people.
我第一次教课是在2021年夏天 我知道这对很多人来说可能已经是很久以前的事了
Makes me feel a little old to say that, but it's true.
说出来让我觉得自己有点老了 但这是真的
I'm originally from Tampa Bay, Florida.
我来自佛罗里达州的坦帕湾
And I took a gap year to work in industry across a few companies, where I got to actually apply a lot of the skills that I learned from 61B.
我休学一年 在几家公司工作 在那里我真正应用了从61B学到的很多技能
And that is really the subject of this entire lecture.
而这正是整节课的主题
And we're going to talk about some real-life problems.
我们将讨论一些现实生活中的问题
And the problem examples that I give are ones that we've actually built.
我举的例子都是我们实际构建的
And so I'm pretty intimately familiar with them.
所以我对它们非常熟悉
Hopefully, they're kind of interesting to talk about and apply some of these ideas.
希望它们能引起大家的兴趣 并能应用其中的一些想法
And we're going to have a non-recorded question and answer session at the very end, just in the interest of all the NDAs and everything.
为了保密协议 我们将在最后进行一个不录制的问答环节
The content of this lecture has been approved.
这节课的内容已经过批准
So we don't want to interrupt.
所以我们不想打断
I don't want to get in any trouble.
我不想惹麻烦
That being said, the first disclaimer.
话虽如此 先声明一下
Everything that is being said is just my opinion, right?
我所说的一切都只是我的个人意见 对吧？
This is nobody else's opinion in any way, shape, or form.
这绝不是任何其他人以任何方式、形状或形式表达的意见
Nothing contained in these slides is confidential or proprietary information of any company.
这些幻灯片中包含的内容不属于任何公司的机密或专有信息
There are no non-disclosure agreements of any sort being violated here.
这里没有违反任何形式的保密协议
And the sections on complexity and strategic slash tactical programming are inspired by Professor Hug's slides from a few years ago.
关于复杂性和战略/战术编程的部分内容是受几年前Hug教授的幻灯片启发
So the overarching idea behind this whole lecture is that we're going to be talking about what engineering and scale means.
所以这整节课背后的总体思路是 我们将讨论工程和规模的含义
Namely that in 61A, you're focused on the correctness of a program.
也就是说 在61A中 你关注的是程序的正确性
But now in 61B, we're starting to consider there's multiple ways to do things.
但现在在61B中 我们开始考虑有多种方法可以做事情
You have multiple options to build a list.
你有多种选择来构建一个列表
Maybe you build an array list.
也许你构建一个数组列表
Maybe you build a link list.
也许你构建一个链表
Maybe you want to use a map so you have multiple ways of building a tree map or you build a hash map.
也许你想用一个映射 所以你有多种方法来构建一个树映射 或者你构建一个哈希映射
But now you're trying to consider the trade-offs.
但现在你要考虑权衡取舍
Why use a specific option?
为什么要使用特定的选项？
Why not use another one?
为什么不使用另一个呢？
And that's really what engineering is about.
而这正是工程学的意义所在
So you're applying these in larger scale projects.
所以你在更大的项目中应用这些
You now have to abide by some of our requirements, our specifications, so you don't get complete control.
你现在必须遵守一些我们的要求、我们的规范 所以你没有完全的控制权
But you should have noticed by now that compared to the 61A projects, where you had to fill out one function
但你现在应该已经注意到 与61A的项目相比 在那里你必须填写一个函数
and you got a doc string telling you what to do and how to do it, it's a little bit more challenging to take these ideas of design and apply them in reality.
并且有一个文档字符串告诉你做什么以及如何做 将这些设计思想应用到现实中要困难得多
And the best way, of course, to learn that is through examples, through doing it yourself.
当然 学习的最佳方式是通过例子 通过自己动手
That's why we have you do these larger projects.
这就是为什么我们让你做这些更大的项目
But it's also interesting to note that these are just really like a sampling of the larger ideas that's actually a lot more complicated in reality.
但同样有趣的是 要注意到这些实际上只是更大想法的样本 在现实中要复杂得多
And hopefully, this lecture will give some insight into what that looks like.
希望这节课能让你了解一下这些想法是什么样的
Project 3, your next project after Project 2, is about building your own world.
项目3 也就是项目2之后的下一个项目 是关于构建你自己的世界
And really, we try to let you be as creative as you possibly can so that way you get the challenges and the joy and the experiences of building out what it means to design a larger scale project on your own.
实际上 我们尽量让你发挥最大的创造力 这样你就能体验到自己设计一个更大规模项目所带来的挑战、快乐和经验
OK, with that, let's now go into what I mean by code complexity, the first sort of theory part of the lecture.
好的 接下来让我们来了解一下我所说的代码复杂性 这是这节课的第一部分理论内容
And I want to start out with talking actually not about computer science, but more just engineering in general, like all forms of engineering.
我想首先谈谈的实际上不是计算机科学 而是更一般的工程 就像所有形式的工程一样
And it's interesting to note that in other forms of engineering, we're restricted by reality.
有趣的是 在其他形式的工程中 我们受到现实的限制
There's imperfect materials, and so there's only so much that we can do.
材料是不完美的 所以我们能做的事情是有限的
If you want to take an example here, Chemical engineers have to worry about temperature.
如果你想举个例子  化学工程师必须考虑温度
If I'm building, for example, a cup, there's only so many materials that I have.
例如 如果我正在制造一个杯子 我只有这么多材料
There's only so fast that the cup can warm up, the cup can cool.
杯子升温和降温的速度是有限的
There's just certain constraints that we can't really get around no matter what we try to do.
无论我们做什么 都有一些限制是我们无法真正绕过的
The reality is just how it is.
现实就是这样
If I take a look at material scientists, they have to worry about how brittle a material is.
如果我看看材料科学家 他们必须担心材料的脆性
Can a material withstand the kind of stresses that you're going to put on it?
一种材料能承受你将施加的压力吗？
Civil engineers have to worry about construction.
土木工程师必须考虑施工
If I want to build a building that's really, really tall, there's just only so much I can do with concrete and steel reinforcement that I have available to me.
如果我想建造一座非常非常高的建筑 那么我能用混凝土和钢筋做的事情就只有这么多
And so a lot of these disciplines, those are the restrictions.
所以很多学科 这些都是限制
It's a restriction on what you're physically capable of doing that stops you.
限制你的是你实际能做什么
But in computer science, it's actually really interesting to note that, for us, the frontier is not on what we're possibly able to do.
但在计算机科学中 真正有趣的是 对我们来说 前沿不在于我们可能做什么
It's on what we choose to do.
而在于我们选择做什么
Just for context, to get to the moon, the total computing power required for all of the Apollo missions, not just one of them,
为了说明这一点 为了到达月球 所有阿波罗任务（而不仅仅是其中一个）所需的总计算能力
is less than the amount of computing power that you probably have in your pocket right now.
还不如你现在口袋里可能拥有的计算能力
And if you have computers, it's probably many, many more times that.
如果你有电脑 那可能是很多很多倍
And so really, if you want to take a look, it's not about the actual computing power or the ability that we have.
所以真的 如果你想看看 这不是关于我们实际的计算能力或拥有的能力
It's all about how you choose to use that power
而是关于你如何选择使用这种能力
and the mechanisms that you design.
以及你设计的机制
Does anyone recognize what this is, by any chance?
有人认出这是什么吗？
Yeah, do you want to take a guess?
是的 你想猜一下吗？
Yeah, you're exactly correct.
是的 你说得完全正确
That is the ENIAC machine.
那是ENIAC机器
It was built in 1946, released on February 3rd.
它建于1946年 于2月3日发布
And it's basically a bunch of vacuum tubes, all these huge vacuum tubes that effectively act as initial transistors, the actual components within your computer.
它基本上是一堆真空管 所有这些巨大的真空管有效地充当了初始晶体管 也就是你电脑中的实际组件
It's a huge room.
这是一个巨大的房间
And it was only used for very limited tasks.
它只用于非常有限的任务
But at the time, it was considered a supercomputer.
但在当时 它被认为是一台超级计算机
It was so powerful, so advanced, it was 1,000 times faster than anything else at the time.
它太强大了 太先进了 比当时任何东西都快1000倍
But for all intents and purposes, it was effectively a large calculator.
但实际上 它就是一个大型计算器
We couldn't run things like Microsoft Office.
我们不能运行像Microsoft Office这样的东西
You couldn't log on to Ed via the ENIAC.
你不能通过ENIAC登录Ed
There was no concept of the internet.
那时还没有互联网的概念
And so it was just a really large machine and still facing a lot of material constraints.
所以它只是一台非常大的机器 仍然面临着许多材料的限制
Has anyone ever played this game before, RollerCoaster Tycoon?
有人玩过这款游戏吗？《过山车大亨》？
Okay, cool, a few hands.
好的 酷 有几个人玩过
This game is really interesting because it was released in 1999.
这款游戏非常有趣 因为它是在1999年发布的
And as a part of being released in 1999 is that you had to run on computers that existed in 1999.
因为是在 1999 年发布的 所以你必须在 1999 年存在的电脑上运行
So those computers are not
所以那些电脑并不是
It's not really that great.
并不是那么好
And so you had to build an assembly.
所以你必须构建一个汇编程序
Assembly is actual machine-level code.
汇编程序是实际的机器级代码
And so you're thinking about, what parts of the CPU do you move memory around and into?
所以你在思考 CPU 的哪些部分可以用来移动内存？
How do you interface with your actual RAM?
如何与实际的 RAM 进行交互？
How do you interface with your hard drive?
如何与硬盘进行交互？
It's very complicated.
非常复杂
It's a very difficult language to understand, because it's not very intuitive for humans.
这是一种很难理解的语言 因为它对人类来说不是很直观
It's a machine language, after all.
毕竟是机器语言
Only 1% is written in C, which is considered a higher-level language, where you get variables and more traditional for loops and conditionals.
只有 1% 是用 C 语言编写的 C 语言被认为是一种更高级的语言 它有变量 更传统的循环和条件语句
But it was written this way because it had to be.
但它之所以这样写是因为它必须这样写
In order to support the functionality that comes with building your own roller coaster world and have it run in a meaningful way, you kind of had to deal with this whole assembly thing.
为了支持构建你自己的过山车世界并使其以有意义的方式运行 你不得不处理整个汇编程序的事情
But it's very, very difficult for programmers to reason about.
但这对程序员来说很难理解
So if you want to take a look, this is an example of what it looks like.
如果你想看看 这是一个例子 它看起来像这样
It's a little bit of an outdated graphic, but there's just a lot going on.
这是一个有点过时的图形 但是有很多东西在发生
And so it's very challenging for computers to handle that kind of task.
所以 计算机处理这种任务是非常具有挑战性的
The game was designed for Intel Pentium CPUs.
这款游戏是为 Intel Pentium CPU 设计的
So at that time, the cutting edge was around 66 million operations per second.
所以在那时 最先进的技术大约是每秒 6600 万次操作
Anyone want to take a guess as to how many operations we can do now?
有人想猜猜我们现在可以做多少次操作吗？
66 billion?
660 亿？
You're actually very close.
你实际上非常接近了
It's 6 billion.
是 60 亿
But it's still like 100 times more.
但它仍然是 100 倍以上
And it turns out that that's the gap that we need to now be able to build a lot more generalizable things, where we don't have to build programs in assembly anymore.
事实证明 这就是我们现在需要能够构建更多通用事物的差距 我们不再需要用汇编语言构建程序
Even the lowest level that you go is probably something like C++.
即使是最低的级别 你可能也会用到像 C++ 这样的语言
And we're able to leverage a lot of these more advanced computers for our tasks.
我们能够利用很多这些更先进的计算机来完成我们的任务
Do we have any questions on Zoom?
在 Zoom 上有没有什么问题？
OK, cool.
好的 酷
So we've talked a lot about how this software works.
所以我们已经谈了很多关于这个软件是如何工作的
And I want to give one more example, just in the modern day, to really just drive home the point that I'm making,
我想再举一个例子 就在现代 来真正说明我想要表达的观点
那就是如果你看看今天的电子游戏 它们需要 3.5 GHz 和 8 GB 的 RAM
which is that if you look at video games today, they require 3.5 gigahertz and 8 gigs of RAM.
And in 1996, you only had 8 megabytes or 16 megabytes of RAM.
而在 1996 年 你只有 8 MB 或 16 MB 的 RAM
So it's literally a difference of 1,000 times.
所以这实际上是 1000 倍的差距
And that difference matters, because it means that the average software product does not require the full computing power that you have.
这种差距很重要 因为它意味着一般的软件产品不需要你拥有的全部计算能力
If you have a computer, you expect it to be able to run a lot of different programs.
如果你有一台电脑 你希望它能够运行很多不同的程序
You expect to be able to play a game, to have a browser open, to have a music player open, to be texting your friends.
你希望能够玩游戏 打开浏览器 打开音乐播放器 给朋友发短信
There's just a lot of things that you expect your computer to be able to do, but it's easy to forget just how much and how powerful it is.
你希望你的电脑能够做很多事情 但你很容易忘记它有多强大
So here's an example of a game where, if you look at the minimum requirements, the minimum memory requirement is 2 gigabytes.
所以这里有一个游戏的例子 如果你看看最低要求 最低内存要求是 2 GB
The minimum processor is over 3 gigahertz.
最低处理器超过 3 GHz
And remember that we were measuring in megahertz, which is 1,000 times slower just a few slides before.
请记住 我们之前是用 MHz 来衡量的 它比几张幻灯片前的速度慢 1000 倍
Anyone know what game this is?
有人知道这是什么游戏吗？
You can take a guess.
你可以猜猜看
I think it's kind of hard to guess the game based on the requirements since they're kind of shared.
我认为根据要求很难猜出游戏 因为它们有点相似
It's actually, yeah, it's Minecraft.
实际上 是的 它是 Minecraft
That's exactly, okay, first guess.
没错 好吧 第一次就猜对了
I put Minecraft on here because Minecraft was originally built in Java, which is the language that I know everyone in here loves so much.
我把 Minecraft 放在这里是因为 Minecraft 最初是用 Java 构建的 我知道这里的每个人都非常喜欢 Java 语言
So, yeah, so this is actually what Minecraft requires, right?
所以 是的 这就是 Minecraft 需要的 对吧？
And it doesn't seem like a crazy game, but it requires all these fancy things that we have in our computers today.
它看起来不像是一个疯狂的游戏 但它需要我们今天电脑中的所有这些高级功能
So really, the important takeaway from the past few minutes should be that the limitation on what you can build really comes in the way that you design things.
所以 在过去的几分钟里 真正重要的收获应该是 对你能够构建的东西的限制实际上来自于你设计事物的方式
It's the way that you plan things, not in the resources that you have available to you.
这是你计划事物的方式 而不是你拥有的资源
There are a couple implications of this.
这其中有一些含义
The first one is that you can't take an individual programmer and manage a large software system yourself, because now these systems
第一个是你不能让一个程序员自己管理一个大型软件系统 因为现在这些系统变得如此庞大
are growing so large and so powerful and so capable that it's not feasible to have just one person building out a project by themselves.
如此强大 如此有能力 以至于让一个人自己构建一个项目是不可能的
And an extension of that is that if you did have a lot of people, if each one can't understand the entire code base, then each one should only have to understand a fraction of the code base.
它的延伸是 如果你确实有很多程序员 如果每个人都不能理解整个代码库 那么每个人都应该只需要理解代码库的一小部分
And this is important because it changes how we think about setting up a code base.
这一点很重要 因为它改变了我们对设置代码库的思考方式
It changes how we think about setting up project structure, files, functions, modules, a lot of whole things that we're going to talk about in just a moment.
它改变了我们对设置项目结构、文件、函数、模块的思考方式 很多我们马上要讨论的事情
We now transition into formalizing this idea that comes from everything we just talked about, which we can wrap in this thing called complexity.
现在我们过渡到将这个想法形式化 这个想法来自我们刚刚谈论的所有内容 我们可以把它包装在这个叫做复杂性的东西中
And complexity, as it's defined here, is not runtime complexity.
这里的复杂性 并不是运行时复杂性
It's not spacetime complexity like you saw with asymptotics.
它不是像你在渐近线中看到的那样的时空复杂性
Instead, now we're talking about code complexity.
相反 现在我们谈论的是代码复杂性
John Ousterhout, he used to be a professor here at Berkeley.
John Ousterhout 他曾经是伯克利的一名教授
And then he left to go to Sun Microsystems, who actually built the original Java.
然后他离开去了 Sun Microsystems Sun Microsystems 实际上构建了最初的 Java
They were acquired by Oracle in 2009.
他们在 2009 年被 Oracle 收购了
So whenever you go to the Java docs, that's why you go to the Oracle website.
所以每当你访问 Java 文档时 这就是为什么你要去 Oracle 网站
So he went to Sun Microsystems.
所以他去了 Sun Microsystems
And then now he teaches at a small school in Palo Alto that
然后现在他在帕洛阿尔托的一所小型学校教书 那所学校
People probably not have heard of, called Stanford.
人们可能没有听说过 叫做斯坦福
And he defines this as anything related to the structure of a software system that makes it hard to understand and modify it.
他将复杂性定义为与软件系统的结构相关的任何东西 这些东西使它难以理解和修改
That's what complexity is all about, which sounds a little broad.
这就是复杂性的全部 这听起来有点宽泛
But in reality, the idea is just like, if we have more features in a program, it becomes more complex.
但实际上 这个想法就像 如果我们在一个程序中添加更多功能 它就会变得更复杂
But our goal here is to make software simple.
但我们的目标是让软件变得简单
And it sounds weird at first, because if you think about what's most impressive, what's most impressive are the really complex programs.
这听起来一开始很奇怪 因为如果你想什么最令人印象深刻 最令人印象深刻的是那些非常复杂的程序
It sounds a lot cooler to tell your friend, hey, I just built a program that has 6,000 lines, versus telling your friend, hey, I built a program that has only 60.
告诉你的朋友 嘿 我刚刚构建了一个有 6000 行的程序 听起来比告诉你的朋友 嘿 我构建了一个只有 60 行的程序酷多了
It sounds a lot easier.
听起来容易多了
It sounds a lot simpler.
听起来简单多了
And in many ways, complexity seems to be this goal.
在很多方面 复杂性似乎是这个目标
But in reality, it's the enemy.
但实际上 它是敌人
We want to avoid it as much as we possibly can.
我们想要尽可能地避免它
And you might ask why.
你可能会问为什么
Well, the short version is that it requires a lot of effort to make small improvements.
好吧 简而言之 它需要大量的努力才能做出小的改进
And that's kind of the opposite of what we want to do.
而这与我们想要做的正好相反
To break it down further, first of all, it's hard to understand how your code works.
进一步分解 首先 很难理解你的代码是如何工作的
If I have code that's very complicated, a lot of if statements just really nested, it can be hard to look at and figure out what's going on.
如果我的代码非常复杂 很多 if 语句嵌套在一起 就很难看懂发生了什么
If you go to office hours and you show a TA your code and it takes like five, six minutes or your 10 minutes a lot just to explain the code, well, it's probably because the code is very complex.
如果你去办公时间 向助教展示你的代码 花了五、六分钟或者十分钟来解释代码 那么 这可能是因为代码非常复杂
And it's something that's hard to avoid.
这是很难避免的事情
Secondly, it's also difficult to fix bugs.
其次 修复错误也很困难
This extends from the first point, which is, if you don't really understand what's happening in the first place, you don't know what you need to change to get your intended functionality.
这是第一点的延伸 那就是 如果你真的不理解首先发生了什么 你就不知道你需要改变什么来获得你想要的功能
And even further, if you want to add a new function, a new feature, you probably don't know what it is that you need to change with confidence.
更进一步 如果你想添加一个新函数 一个新功能 你可能不知道你需要自信地改变什么
There's an idea here called unknown unknowns, which is not that you don't know what you need to change.
这里有一个叫做未知的未知的想法 它不是你不知道你需要改变什么
It's that you don't even know what you don't know to change.
而是你甚至不知道你不知道要改变什么
You're confused on what questions to ask, what parts of the code base to look at, where to even get started.
你不知道该问什么问题 该看代码库的哪些部分 甚至不知道从哪里开始
And this is actually really common in large code bases.
这在大型代码库中实际上很常见
So all the really big companies, like Google, for example, if you went to Google and you try to fix their search engine, it's going to be a massive code base, millions and millions of lines.
所以所有的大公司 比如 Google 如果你去了 Google 试图修复他们的搜索引擎 它将是一个巨大的代码库 数百万行
If you go to Microsoft and you try to look at Windows and how it's built, again, it's going to be millions and millions of lines.
如果你去 Microsoft 试图查看 Windows 及其构建方式 它也将是数百万行代码
And it goes back to that point that we talked about earlier, where one programmer cannot understand the entire code base that you have on large software projects.
这又回到了我们之前谈到的那个观点 即在一个大型软件项目中 一个程序员无法理解整个代码库
So here's an example from Spotify.
这是一个来自 Spotify 的例子
Anyone here use Spotify?
这里有人用 Spotify 吗？
A lot of people.
很多人
It doesn't really seem that complicated.
它看起来并不复杂
It's just a music app.
它只是一个音乐应用程序
But they have a billion lines of code.
但它们有 10 亿行代码
And they use 60 million of those in production.
他们在生产中使用了 6000 万行代码
It sounds like a lot.
听起来很多
If you want to take a look at this graph, you can see that the number of engineers that they hired to maintain all of this kind of increases at a linear rate.
如果你想看看这张图 你可以看到他们雇佣的工程师数量以线性速度增长 以维护所有这些代码
But the number of components, the actual code that they're writing, increases at an exponential rate.
但组件的数量 也就是他们实际编写的代码 却以指数速度增长
But if you think about the features that Spotify has, it doesn't feel like they have a billion lines of code.
但是 如果你想想 Spotify 的功能 它并没有 10 亿行代码的感觉
Sure, I guess I can make a queue, and I can add friends.
当然 我想我可以创建一个队列 我可以添加朋友
But it doesn't really sound that hard.
但这听起来并不难
And it just goes to show that even those very simple examples can still spiral out.
这说明即使是很简单的例子 也会变得复杂起来
We can generalize this by saying that complexity in general will scale exponentially.
我们可以概括地说 复杂性通常会呈指数级增长
And the reason why is that every single time you add a new feature, it has to interact with all of your old features.
原因是每次添加新功能时 它都必须与所有旧功能进行交互
So if Spotify has your play and pause functionality, and then you want to add a cue, well, now you have to answer all these other questions.
例如 如果 Spotify 有播放和暂停功能 然后你想添加一个队列 那么你就必须回答所有这些其他问题
Like, if you add a song to the cue, does it go at the end of the cue?
比如 如果你把一首歌添加到队列中 它会放在队列的末尾吗？
Does it go at the beginning of the cue?
它会放在队列的开头吗？
If it goes at the end of the cue and you hit skip, does it go to the next song that used to be on the cue?
如果它放在队列的末尾 你按下跳过 它会跳到队列中以前的那首歌吗？
Or does it go to the new song that's on the cue?
还是会跳到队列中的新歌？
If you add a song to the end of the queue, but for some reason, it gets taken down as a copyright violation, what happens now?
如果你把一首歌添加到队列的末尾 但由于某种原因 它因为版权问题被下架了 现在会发生什么？
Do you skip to the next song?
你会跳到下一首歌吗？
Does that song disappear?
那首歌会消失吗？
Does the user see it?
用户会看到它吗？
Does it gray out?
它会变灰吗？
I can just keep going and going and going, just making up scenarios.
我可以一直不停地想出各种场景
But it goes to show, every single time you make one change, you have to evaluate how that change affects everything that came before it.
但这说明 每次你进行一次更改时 都必须评估该更改如何影响之前的所有内容
So the graph really looks like this.
所以图实际上是这样的
And a lot of the times, when you're working on smaller-scale projects, you're on the left-hand side of this,
很多时候 当你处理较小规模的项目时 你是在这个图的左边
where you're adding all these functions, and you're like, hey, it's not really getting that complex.
你添加了所有这些功能 然后你会觉得 嘿 它并没有变得那么复杂
But the second you start stepping over into the right-hand side of it, each small little function starts adding more and more complexity.
但是一旦你开始进入图的右边 每一个小的功能都会增加越来越多的复杂性
This is why sometimes you'll see software companies say, oh, we had a regression, or oh, unfortunately, our services are down.
这就是为什么有时候你会看到软件公司说 哦 我们遇到了一个回归 或者哦 不幸的是 我们的服务中断了
Because they may not be adding what seems like a complicated thing, but in the context of everything else they've built, it really does add up over time.
因为他们可能并没有添加看起来很复杂的东西 但在他们构建的所有其他东西的背景下 它确实随着时间的推移而累积起来
So we have a lot of talk about complexity, and we're now going to break it down into two kinds of complexity to figure out what we can do here.
所以我们谈论了很多关于复杂性的内容 现在我们将把它分解成两种类型的复杂性 以弄清楚我们能做什么
And the first kind is our avoidable complexity.
第一种是我们可以避免的复杂性
It's that there are certain kinds of complexity, sorry, our unavoidable complexity, which are there's certain kind of complexity that's just inherent in what we're doing.
也就是说 某些类型的复杂性 抱歉 是我们不可避免的复杂性 这些复杂性是我们正在做的事情中固有的
If I'm building Spotify, I just have to build functionality that allows me to press play, allows me to press pause, allows me to skip songs.
如果我正在构建 Spotify 我只需要构建允许我按下播放、暂停和跳过歌曲的功能
And there's just only so much I can do about it.
对此我能做的也就这么多了
I guess technically, you don't have to.
我猜从技术上讲 你不必这样做
But at that point, you're not really making Spotify.
但在那一点上 你就不是真的在做 Spotify 了
You're just making an application, I guess, if you're not able to play the music.
如果你不能播放音乐 我猜你只是在做一个应用程序
But that part is required.
但那部分是必需的
And so we can't really escape that part of the complexity.
所以我们无法真正逃避复杂性的那部分
But the second part we can do something about.
但第二部分我们可以做些什么
And the second part is the avoidable complexity.
第二部分是可以避免的复杂性
And that has to do with the decisions that we make, what we have control over.
这与我们做出的决定有关 与我们所能控制的东西有关
And a response to avoidable complexity.
以及对可避免复杂性的回应
There's a couple of things we can do.
我们可以做几件事
The first thing is we can make code simpler and more obvious.
第一件事是我们可以让代码更简单、更清晰
The idea being that code should be very intuitive for someone to understand.
其理念是代码应该非常直观 易于理解
You show it to someone.
你把它展示给某人看
You have nice variable names.
你有很好的变量名
It follows a good structure.
它遵循良好的结构
It makes sense as to what is going on.
它让人明白发生了什么
A great example here is Project One.
这里有一个很好的例子 就是 Project One
A lot of people use Sentinel nodes.
很多人使用 Sentinel 节点
And Sentinel nodes are so great because if you try to deal with the case that you have no nodes in your linkless deck,
Sentinel 节点之所以如此出色 是因为如果你试图处理链表中没有节点的情况
You don't have to worry about all the minutiae.
你就不必担心所有细节
You don't have to worry about initializing a new node, any null pointer exceptions, anything like that, because you handle these pointers.
你不必担心初始化新节点、任何空指针异常之类的事情 因为你处理了这些指针
And so you're able to handle every case with just one case.
因此 你能够用一种情况处理所有情况
It's a really powerful programming paradigm that hopefully you noticed made the programming a lot easier for you to reason about.
这是一种非常强大的编程范式 希望你注意到它让你的编程更容易理解
And second is we can use modules, where we're able to leverage this idea called abstraction, which is that we black box some idea.
其次 我们可以使用模块 我们可以利用这种叫做抽象的概念 也就是我们将某个想法黑盒化
And I tell you generally, oh, this is how you interface with it, and this is what it will give you.
我一般会告诉你 哦 这是你与它交互的方式 这是它会给你的东西
But I don't go into any detail about how it actually works under the hood.
但我不会详细说明它实际上是如何工作的
So a great example here is an interface from Java.
所以这里有一个很好的例子 来自 Java 的接口
So if I tell you that I have a map, that just told you a lot of information without telling you how it works.
如果我告诉你我有一个 map 那就相当于告诉你很多信息 而没有告诉你它是如何工作的
A map tells you that you can put some information, create a key-value pair, and get that value given some key.
map 告诉你 你可以放入一些信息 创建一个键值对 然后根据某个键获取该值
You have other functions, too.
你还有其他功能
You can get the key set.
你可以获取键集
You can get the value set.
你可以获取值集
You can iterate over it.
你可以遍历它
You can do all these fancy things.
你可以做所有这些花哨的事情
But we never go into how it's implemented.
但我们从来没有深入探讨过它是如何实现的
So I could choose to have a hash map.
所以我可以选择使用 hash map
I could choose to have a BST map.
我也可以选择使用 BST map
But the map itself is a general module that we can leverage.
但是 map 本身是一个我们可以利用的通用模块
I included one last slide on this section about the relevance.
我在这一节的最后一页包含了一张关于相关性的幻灯片
And the reason why is that I think last semester, a lot of the feedback from students was like, oh, this is great.
原因是 我认为上学期 很多学生的反馈都是这样的 哦 这很棒
Complexity sounds cool.
复杂性听起来很酷
But all the examples seem to be very software-specific.
但所有的例子似乎都与软件很相关
And I don't really care.
而我并不真的关心
I'm just kind of here.
我只是来这里学习的
And I have my midterm to worry about and my projects to worry about.
我还要担心我的期中考试和我的项目
I get that.
我明白
I hear you.
我听到了
So I wanted to throw this slide in here.
所以我想把这张幻灯片放在这里
It's why I think this matters.
这就是为什么我认为这很重要
And a huge component here is that tackling complexity from software scale is actually a lot more common than you think.
这里的一个重要组成部分是 从软件规模上解决复杂性实际上比你想象的要普遍得多
Any field that's adjacent to software is going to run into these kinds of issues and run into the implications that Ruck caused from this.
任何与软件相邻的领域都会遇到这类问题 并遇到 Ruck 造成的这种影响
So an example is software engineering.
例如软件工程
All the examples I gave about Spotify go into that.
我关于 Spotify 的所有例子都说明了这一点
But another example is data science.
另一个例子是数据科学
Any time that you're building a data pipeline, which is where you're taking a lot of data that comes from how users interact with your product, and then you're trying to transform that into actionable insights.
任何时候你都在构建数据管道 也就是你从用户如何与你的产品交互中获取大量数据 然后你试图将其转化为可操作的见解
Maybe you're trying to create a chart.
也许你正在尝试创建一个图表
Maybe Spotify is trying to predict what sort of users in what region are more likely to buy premium.
也许 Spotify 正在尝试预测哪些地区的哪些用户更有可能购买高级版
That's pretty valuable to them.
这对他们来说很有价值
And that whole data pipeline process has a lot of code to it, has a lot of things that they have to analyze and track.
而整个数据管道过程涉及到很多代码 有很多东西需要分析和跟踪
Machine learning models, if you're interested in building those, are also quite complicated.
如果你有兴趣构建机器学习模型 它们也相当复杂
They have their own version control systems.
它们有自己的版本控制系统
You have a team of people working on it.
你有一个团队在负责它
You have to coordinate between a lot of things and achieve a lot of tasks.
你必须协调很多事情并完成很多任务
Human-computer interaction, if you're trying to build a system like Spotify, as you include more and more functionality, you have to think about where all the buttons are going to be.
人机交互 如果你试图构建像 Spotify 这样的系统 随着你包含越来越多的功能 你必须考虑所有按钮的位置
How are people going to look at it and use the product?
人们将如何看待和使用该产品？
There's a lot of things that happen with everything we just talked about, how every single time you add a new function, a new feature, you have to think about how it interfaces with everything else.
我们刚才谈到的所有内容 每次你添加一个新功能 一个新特性 你都必须考虑它如何与其他所有东西交互 都会发生很多事情
Still applies here.
仍然适用于这里
Even analysts, too.
甚至分析师也是如此
So a business analyst, a computer analyst, a data analyst, they all have to work in the same idea, which is that as you add these more functions,
所以业务分析师、计算机分析师、数据分析师 他们都必须在同一个理念下工作
as you add these more features, any time you're software adjacent, you still have to deal with the implications that come from that.
那就是随着你添加更多功能 更多特性 任何时候你与软件相邻 你仍然必须处理由此带来的影响
There's a lot more.
还有很多
The key idea here from this whole section is just that you have to manage functionality and your interactions with programs.
本节的要点是 你必须管理功能以及你与程序的交互
OK, so now we are going to talk about some frameworks that we can use to address all of this stuff that I just talked about with code complexity.
好 现在我们来聊聊一些框架 可以用它们来解决我刚才提到的代码复杂性问题
And we're going to start with something called tactical programming.
我们将从“战术编程”开始
And as the name implies, the idea is that you're focusing on specific tactics.
顾名思义 它的理念是专注于特定的战术
You just want to get something working really quickly.
你只想快速让一些东西跑起来
And so you're going to leverage a lot of workarounds and a lot of shortcuts to get this done.
所以你会利用很多变通方法和捷径来完成这件事
So here's an example.
举个例子
Maybe this sounds familiar.
也许这听起来很熟悉
I know that when I took the class, this was me a lot of the time, which is that if your code doesn't pass a test,
我记得我上课的时候 很多时候我就是这样的：如果你的代码没有通过测试
you go back to your code and you add an if statement to handle that one case, and then you run the test again.
你就回到代码中 添加一个 if 语句来处理那个特定的情况 然后你再次运行测试
And then by adding that if statement, the test that you passed previously now fail.
然后 通过添加那个 if 语句 你之前通过的测试现在失败了
And so now you're trying to figure out, well, what if statement do I add?
所以现在你在想 好吧 我该添加什么 if 语句呢？
So you go back and you add two more if statements, one for each individual case, and then you fail now a different set of tests.
所以你回去 为每个单独的情况添加两个 if 语句 然后你现在又失败了一组不同的测试
Does that sound familiar to anyone?
这听起来对任何人熟悉吗？
That's actually exactly how I approach the class.
那实际上就是我上课的方式
And I think that that is something that is sometimes true.
我认为这有时确实如此
There are actual applications of this.
它确实有实际应用
So if you're building a prototype, if you're building a proof of concept, maybe you're working on a startup, and you have a pitch to some VC fund.
所以 如果你正在构建一个原型 如果你正在构建一个概念验证 也许你正在创业 并且你要向某个风险投资基金做演示
They want to see a quick demo.
他们想看一个快速的演示
They don't really care that your code is maintainable, or they don't really care about any of the complexity stuff that we just talked about.
他们并不真正在乎你的代码是否可维护 或者他们并不真正在乎我们刚才谈论的任何复杂性问题
But they want to see something work.
但他们想看到一些东西能运行
So in that case, it makes a lot of sense.
所以在那种情况下 这很有意义
But in general, there are some issues, as you can kind of tell where I'm going with this.
但总的来说 有一些问题 就像你可以猜到我要说的那样
The first one being that we didn't really spend any time on the design.
第一个问题是 我们没有真正花时间在设计上
We're just trying to get something working.
我们只是想让一些东西能运行
And so if that's your goal, you're trying to modify your code and try to push it into this thing that works.
所以 如果这是你的目标 你就会试图修改你的代码 并试图把它推到这个能运行的东西里
Second is that it's also very complicated.
第二点是它也很复杂
The more if statements, the more edge cases that you're trying to handle, the more complicated your code becomes.
你试图处理的 if 语句越多 边缘情况越多 你的代码就越复杂
And also, if you want to refactor, if you do realize, hey, I actually want to restart, I thought of a different way to do this, you might have to restart.
而且 如果你想重构 如果你确实意识到 嘿 我实际上想重新开始 我想到了一个不同的方法来做这件事 你可能必须重新开始
And a great example of this is project 2.
一个很好的例子就是项目2
If you missed the runtime requirements part in the spec of how every method is supposed to operate, and you built a constructor
如果你错过了规范中关于每个方法应该如何操作的运行时要求部分 并且你构建了一个构造函数
that just takes in all the files and just keeps them as strings, well, now you have to go back, delete the constructor, delete all the work
它只接受所有文件并将它们保留为字符串 那么 现在你必须返回 删除构造函数
that you had on every single method, and go back to square one and plan how are you going to attack the runtime requirements.
删除你在每个方法上的所有工作 然后回到起点 并计划如何处理运行时要求
And this is actually a very powerful idea because that prototype that I talked about before often actually gets deployed into the real world due to a lack of time.
这实际上是一个非常强大的想法 因为我之前谈到的那个原型 由于缺乏时间 通常实际上会被部署到现实世界中
So it turns out that a lot of early startups, a lot of early companies that are using these workarounds end up pushing that code into the real world.
所以事实证明 很多早期的初创公司 很多使用这些变通方法的早期公司 最终都会将这些代码推向现实世界
So Microsoft is actually a pretty good example of this.
微软实际上就是一个很好的例子
When they built Windows way back when, a lot of their legacy code still exists in the code base today.
当他们在很久以前构建 Windows 时 他们的很多遗留代码仍然存在于今天的代码库中
It's actually so hard to try to get rid of it that their approach is just like they just add new functionality on top of it.
实际上 想要摆脱它太难了 所以他们的方法就像是在上面添加新功能一样
So in Windows, you have a control panel.
所以在 Windows 中 你有一个控制面板
And then they wanted to make a new setting system.
然后他们想做一个新的设置系统
And so they just built a new setting system.
所以他们就构建了一个新的设置系统
And then there's also the old control panel there, because you just can't remove it.
然后还有旧的控制面板在那里 因为你就是无法删除它
So it's very important to notice that it seems like in an idealistic world, no company obviously would ever do this.
所以 重要的是要注意 在理想世界中 显然没有哪家公司会这样做
But it's actually a lot more common than it seems.
但这实际上比看起来要普遍得多
So the other one that we can do is strategic programming.
所以我们可以做的另一个是“战略编程”
Instead of doing just the specific tactic, we think about this more generally.
我们不是只做特定的战术 而是更普遍地考虑这个问题
The key word here is we think about long-term strategy.
这里的关键词是我们考虑长期战略
So we're thinking, in the future, how might we design code that's best maintainable and is elegant?
所以我们在思考 未来 我们如何才能设计出最易于维护和优雅的代码？
The problem is that it takes a little longer, but we want code to be maintainable.
问题是这需要更长的时间 但我们希望代码是可维护的
If I have code, I should be able to update it over time.
如果我有一段代码 我应该能够随着时间的推移更新它
I should be able to fix bugs.
我应该能够修复错误
I should be able to change things.
我应该能够改变一些东西
We want it to be simple, which means that if I showed someone the code, if someone else had to take over and maintain this for me, then they would be able to do it.
我们希望它是简单的 这意味着如果我向某人展示了代码 如果其他人必须接手并为我维护它 那么他们就能够做到
And the third thing is that it's future-proof.
第三点是它是面向未来的
We want to design code that's able to last many, many decades into the future.
我们想要设计能够在未来几十年中持续存在的代码
And so a lot of actual banks struggle with this idea, because they use something called Yes.
所以很多银行都在为这个想法而苦苦挣扎 因为他们使用了一种叫做 COBOL 的东西
Yes, that's actually a really good point.
是的 这确实是一个很好的观点
And you beat me to this next bullet.
你在下一个要点上抢先了我
So the question is, what do I mean by maintain?
所以问题是 我所说的“维护”是什么意思？
Don't we just throw away the code once we're done?
我们完成代码后不就扔掉了吗？
And you're right.
你说得对
In classes, every single time you build a project, you're done.
在课堂上 每次你构建一个项目 你就完成了
Maybe the project lasts throughout the class.
也许这个项目会持续整个课程
But between courses, there is no extension.
但在课程之间 没有扩展
But if you're building something that is a larger project, maybe you're working on a research paper, maybe you're working on a research model, maybe you're building a company.
但是 如果你正在构建一个更大的项目 也许你正在写一篇研究论文 也许你正在研究一个研究模型 也许你正在创办一家公司
You can't just throw it away.
你不能就这样把它扔掉
If you're Microsoft and you're building,
如果你是微软 你正在构建
I like Windows.
我喜欢 Windows
I use it a lot.
我经常使用它
That's why I keep referencing in the examples.
这就是为什么我一直在例子中提到它
But maybe you're building Spotify.
也许你正在构建 Spotify
If you're building Spotify, you can't treat Spotify as, oh, I just need it working right now.
如果你正在构建 Spotify 你不能把 Spotify 当成 哦 我现在只需要它能运行就行了
Because there's going to be a time in maybe the next few months, maybe the next year, maybe the next decade,
where you start facing more and more issues with how streaming works, with how video works, with how music works, all those kinds of things.
因为在接下来的几个月、明年 甚至十年内 你可能会开始面临越来越多的问题
比如流媒体如何工作、视频如何工作、音乐如何工作 所有这些事情
And so when we think about these larger-scale projects, maintainability actually matters a lot for us.
所以 当我们考虑这些更大规模的项目时 可维护性实际上对我们来说非常重要
Does that make sense?
这有道理吗？
Kind of?
有点？
OK, I'll take it.
好的 我接受
Yeah, so like I was saying, so we want to have this idea of future-proofness for our projects.
是的 就像我说的 所以我们希望我们的项目具有面向未来的特性
Another huge thing is that when we have our strategy and sometimes it doesn't work, we just go back to the drawing board.
另一个重要的事情是 当我们有我们的策略 有时它不起作用时 我们就回到绘图板
So it's not required that we have a perfect strategy when we come in.
所以 我们进来的时候并不需要有一个完美的策略
It's more this idea that we update our strategy, we change our strategy, and then we go back and try to implement it.
更重要的是 我们更新我们的策略 我们改变我们的策略 然后我们回去尝试实现它
This is the reason why we have a design document for Project 2B and 2C.
这就是为什么我们为项目 2B 和 2C 有一个设计文档的原因
The point is to try to get you to think about what it is that you're building and how you're building it before you actually start working.
重点是让你在真正开始工作之前 试着思考你正在构建什么 以及你如何构建它
OK, before we go into the first one, let me do a quick check on time.
好的 在我们进入第一个之前 让我快速检查一下时间
OK, we're doing good on time.
好的 我们的时间安排得很好
Cool.
很好
We're now going to switch this lecture from being all this theory and hypotheticals into some real-world examples.
现在 我们将把这节课从所有这些理论和假设转变为一些现实世界的例子
And I'm going to ask you all some questions about how you might approach these ideas and how you might think about approaching the strategy behind building these.
我将问你们一些关于你们如何处理这些想法的问题 以及你们如何思考构建这些想法背后的策略
So let's start with this first one, which is about resource configurations and testing, which doesn't really sound like it means anything.
让我们从第一个开始 它是关于资源配置和测试的 这听起来好像没有任何意义
So let's try to explain what it means.
所以让我们试着解释一下它的含义
So the context here is that I worked at this company called Retool back in fall 2022.
所以这里的背景是 我在 2022 年秋季在这家叫做 Retool 的公司工作
And they build internal tools, which sounds a little weird, I will admit.
他们构建内部工具 这听起来有点奇怪 我承认
But here's some context, like what I mean by internal tools.
但这里有一些背景 就像我所说的内部工具
So let's say that you make a survey.
假设你做了一个调查
So maybe you build a Google Form, and you send it out to a bunch of people.
也许你构建了一个 Google 表单 并将其发送给一大群人
And they all respond.
他们都做出了回应
And then you export this data out to Google Sheets.
然后你将这些数据导出到 Google Sheets
You click the Link with Sheets button.
你点击“链接到表格”按钮
And then you get this nice spreadsheet of everyone's responses, their time, their individual question answers.
然后你就会得到一个包含每个人回复的漂亮电子表格 他们的时间 他们每个问题的答案
Let's say you want to build a dashboard.
假设你想要构建一个仪表板
So think about it as a website that people can go onto, and they see the most common responses from your survey.
可以把它想象成一个网站 人们可以访问它 然后他们会看到你调查中最常见的回复
So in order to do that, you have to build an actual website.
所以为了做到这一点 你必须构建一个真正的网站
We call this a front end to display the results of what's happening.
我们称之为“前端” 用于显示正在发生的事情的结果
You have to build a server.
你必须构建一个服务器
We call this a back end to actually go and get your resources for you, to get the data from the Google Sheets.
我们称之为“后端” 它实际上会去获取你的资源 从 Google Sheets 中获取数据
And then you also have to maintain and develop both.
然后你还必须维护和开发这两者
If you want this to be a lasting service, maybe one that people even pay for, they're going to demand
如果你希望这是一个持久化的服务 甚至是一个人们愿意付费的服务
that it lasts for some period of time, that it's reliable, that it's up, that they can use it when they need to.
他们会要求它持续运行一段时间 可靠、稳定 并且在需要时可以使用
So instead of doing all of this, the idea behind Retool was that you just wrote one query, and then you link it to drag and drop components.
所以Retool的思路是 你只需编写一个查询 然后将其链接到拖放组件 而不是做所有这些事情
So instead of maintaining your website and your server, Retool kind of handles that both for you, and then you just tell Retool what to do, and they take care of the code details.
因此 Retool可以帮你维护网站和服务器 你只需告诉Retool要做什么 他们会处理代码细节
And a lot of this power comes from being able to connect to basically anything.
这种强大的功能很大程度上来自于能够连接到几乎任何东西
They had a lot of options.
他们有很多选择
I want to say it was like 54-plus when I was there.
我想说在我工作的时候有54种以上的选择
It's probably even more now as they've built more integrations.
随着他们构建更多的集成 现在可能更多了
But these all use APIs.
但这些都使用API
And what an API is, is just an interface with working with data.
API只是一个用于处理数据的接口
So we don't care about how it works under the hood.
所以我们不关心它底层的运作方式
And a lot of the times, actually, companies won't tell us how it works under the hood.
实际上 很多时候公司不会告诉我们底层的运作方式
The idea is that you just use this API to describe the structure and the format of the data that you get.
你可以使用这个API来描述你获取的数据的结构和格式
And then you can use it however you'd like.
然后你可以根据需要使用它
So here's a diagram that I made that maybe makes this a little bit clearer.
我做了一个图表 可能会让这更清晰一些
So you have a form.
你有一个表单
That data gets transferred into some sheets that gets used by a server.
数据会被传输到一些表格中 这些表格会被服务器使用
And then you maintain some website where people can log on and view it.
然后你维护一个网站 人们可以在那里登录并查看它
And where Retool comes in is you instead have this arrow where Retool, the quality's not super great on the projector,
Retool的作用是 你拥有这个箭头 其中Retool（投影仪上的质量不太好）
but the idea is that you have all these components over on this side.
但你可以将所有这些组件拖放到这个表格中 这就是你查看 Google Sheet 中所有结果的方式
You can drag and drop it into this table, and that's how you view all the results from the Google Sheet.
任何人都可以参与进来 你可以构建更复杂的功能 并结合其他资源和其他类似的东西
So anyone can come on, and you can build more complex functionality combined with other resources, other things like that.
所以任何人都可以参与进来 你可以构建更复杂的功能 并结合其他资源和其他类似的东西
And so really what we're trying to do is we're trying to solve for this case of the server and the site being gone.
所以我们真正想做的是解决服务器和站点消失的情况
If none of that made any sense, don't worry too much.
如果这些都没有意义 别担心
The only important part is just that we're trying to take some data in.
唯一重要的是我们要获取一些数据
That's it.
就是这样
So what do I mean by that?
我是什么意思呢？
By taking data in, well, the user, of course, has to then tell us what to query from.
通过获取数据 用户当然必须告诉我们从哪里查询
They have to give us the Google Sheets URL.
他们必须提供Google Sheets的URL
They have to tell us how to access their database wherever they're storing their information.
他们必须告诉我们如何访问存储信息的数据库
And that they have to do with these things called resource configurations.
他们必须使用这些叫做资源配置的东西来做这件事
So the idea is to design a system that allows users to put in their information, maybe like a username, a password, a URL, a location.
所以我们的想法是设计一个系统 允许用户输入他们的信息 比如用户名、密码、URL、位置
And then we can go and retrieve that information for them and then show it to them.
然后我们可以去检索这些信息 并展示给他们
So here's an example of what that looks like.
这是一个例子
You can see that if I want to configure a resource that seems to be a data risk resource, I have to give it a name.
你可以看到 如果我想配置一个看起来像数据风险资源的资源 我必须给它一个名字
I have to assign it to some folder.
我必须把它分配给某个文件夹
I have to put in what's called a host name, a port, a path, a catalog, a schema.
我必须输入主机名、端口、路径、目录、模式
I can use a connection string.
我可以使用连接字符串
There's a lot of stuff going on here.
这里有很多东西
The takeaway, though, is that this is like a form.
不过 关键是这就像一个表单
You just go in.
你只需要进去
You put in the necessary information for your specific resource, your specific, for example, Google Sheets.
输入你的特定资源所需的信息 例如 Google Sheet
And then you can walk away with access to that.
然后你就可以访问它了
So that's what we're trying to build, is this literal page, this literal login information screen.
所以这就是我们想要构建的 这个文字页面 这个文字登录信息屏幕
How can we build that for a lot of resources?
我们如何为很多资源构建它？
So one way to do it is to just build a new page.
一种方法是构建一个新页面
Like, there's a new resource, we just make a new page for it.
比如 有一个新的资源 我们就为它创建一个新页面
So if I want Google Sheets, I make a new page for it.
所以如果我想要 Google Sheet 我就为它创建一个新页面
If I want to use an Excel sheet, I make a new page for it.
如果我想使用 Excel 表格 我就为它创建一个新页面
And I keep coding more and more pages every single time for different websites and different web pages.
我不断地为不同的网站和不同的网页编写越来越多的页面
Can anyone think of any issues that might result from this kind of implementation?
谁能想到这种实现方式可能导致的问题？
Yes.
是的
That's a great one.
那是一个很好的例子
There might be inconsistencies.
可能会有不一致的地方
And so if they aren't all coming from one source and you're manually doing it, maybe the wording has changed.
如果它们不是都来自同一个来源 而是你手动完成的 那么措辞可能已经改变了
Maybe the logo has changed.
也许标志已经改变了
Maybe you mess up some spelling error and it keeps going through.
也许你搞砸了一些拼写错误 它一直存在
It's a great point.
这是一个很好的观点
Any others?
还有其他的吗？
Yes.
是的
Exactly, right?
完全正确 对吧？
So now we have a lot of code to maintain because we have different files for every single one.
所以现在我们有很多代码需要维护 因为每个代码都有不同的文件
I think you both nailed it on the head, right?
我想你们都说得很好 对吧？
The idea is if I have one modification, maybe I change something about the functionality.
想法是 如果我有一个修改 也许我改变了关于功能的一些东西
But the key thing is that it actually doesn't have to be about the code.
但关键是 它实际上不必与代码有关
Maybe the marketing department comes to us and says, we have a new logo.
也许市场部门来找我们说 我们有一个新的标志
And you're like, oh, man, now I have to update every single web page over and over.
你会想 哦 伙计 现在我必须一遍又一遍地更新每个网页
And that becomes really annoying, because now you have to go through every single file one by one and update the logo.
这变得非常烦人 因为现在你必须一个一个地浏览每个文件并更新标志
And maybe you're thinking, oh, I just do find and replace, obviously.
也许你在想 哦 我只需要查找和替换 很明显
But what if you have different variations on what you call the logo?
但是如果你对标志的称呼有不同的变化呢？
How do you know what code to search for?
你怎么知道要搜索什么代码？
It starts spiraling a lot out of control very quickly.
它很快就开始失控了
Another one is that sometimes you have breaking changes.
另一个是 有时你会遇到重大变化
Maybe you update the requirements to access Google Sheets, and now that breaks a bunch of pages that rely on it.
也许你更新了访问 Google Sheet 的要求 现在这破坏了一堆依赖它的页面
What if the list interface changed from size to length?
如果列表接口从 size 变成了 length 怎么办？
Every single time you use a list, you have to then go in, find where you use size, and convert it to a dot length in order for your code to work.
每次你使用列表时 你都必须进去 找到你使用 size 的地方 并将其转换为 .length 才能让你的代码工作
And that's really annoying if you have to go through and find every single usage.
如果你必须浏览并找到每个用法 那真的很烦人
In other words, adding a new resource is also complicated.
换句话说 添加新资源也很复杂
And you're basically copying and pasting between pages a lot and trying to figure out where to change.
你基本上是在页面之间进行大量的复制和粘贴 并试图找出在哪里进行更改
And you might forget one small thing to change.
你可能会忘记改变一件小事
And all of a sudden, you have a typo.
突然之间 你打错了字
Customers are getting confused.
顾客们都很困惑
And you're losing money.
你在赔钱
And if you're a company running a business, that matters.
如果你是一家经营企业的公司 那就很重要了
If you lose money, you don't really exist anymore.
如果你赔钱了 你就真的不存在了
So the ultimate solution that we have here is to build a generalized resource config.
所以我们在这里的最终解决方案是构建一个通用的资源配置
So just like how I said earlier that we can have a map, like an interface, it's a very similar idea where we just say we have some properties of a resource.
就像我之前说的 我们可以有一个映射 就像一个接口 这是一个非常类似的想法 我们只是说我们有一些资源的属性
And every single resource will have these properties.
每个资源都将拥有这些属性
Maybe you have some common patterns to generate these inputs.
也许你有一些生成这些输入的通用模式
And then you're going to tell me what those parameters are.
然后你要告诉我那些参数是什么
And we'll go ahead and build it for you.
我们会帮你构建它
Sounds a lot like an interface, because it basically is.
听起来很像一个接口 因为它基本上就是
And this leverages earlier concepts that we talked about.
这利用了我们之前讨论过的概念
So it's a very modular system.
所以这是一个非常模块化的系统
You have this one module.
你拥有这个模块
You pass in the configurations for a resource, and then it generates the page for you.
你传入资源的配置 然后它为你生成页面
And then you also have obviousness.
然后你还有明显的优势
It sounds like there's a person in the middle that's kind of like you hand your requirements to, and then they take control of it.
听起来好像中间有一个人 你把你的要求交给他们 然后他们就控制它
They take care of it for you, and they make sure that it comes out how it needs to.
他们帮你处理它 并确保它按照需要的方式出来
So here's an example of what that looks like.
这是一个例子
So a lot of databases have similar requirements.
所以很多数据库都有类似的要求
So they have a host.
所以他们有一个主机
They have a port.
他们有一个端口
They have a name.
他们有一个名字
Sometimes they have connection options.
有时他们有连接选项
And here's some common examples.
这里有一些常见的例子
This is Postgres and MySQL, which are commonly used in industry.
这是 Postgres 和 MySQL 它们在行业中很常用
Those both have that.
它们都有这些
And so we can treat these as like a pattern.
我们可以把这些当作一种模式
So I have these database-like resources.
所以我有这些类似数据库的资源
The other one is that we have non-database resources.
另一种是我们拥有非数据库资源
And so even in this case, we can still have customized elements so you can pass in your own specialized properties for them to accept.
即使在这种情况下 我们仍然可以拥有自定义元素 因此您可以传入自己的专用属性供它们接受
And so this is really important because now we're overriding the default functionality.
这真的很重要 因为现在我们正在覆盖默认功能
So we have some default functionality that everyone has a host, a port, and a name.
我们有一些默认功能 每个人都有一个主机、一个端口和一个名称
Now we're saying you might not.
现在我们说你可能没有
And that's perfectly fine.
那完全没问题
And we've built in that flexibility into our system.
我们已经在系统中内置了这种灵活性
So an example here is something called Elasticsearch, another one called Databricks.
这里的一个例子是叫做 Elasticsearch 的东西 另一个叫做 Databricks
So now we go into this next idea, which is the stuff that I actually worked on.
现在我们进入下一个想法 这就是我实际工作的内容
Up to this point has been everything that was built before I got there.
到目前为止 所有东西都是在我到达之前构建的
Now we're trying to figure out how to change this.
现在我们正在尝试弄清楚如何改变这一点
And so now we're trying to figure out, OK, well, not all resources might be valid.
所以现在我们正在尝试弄清楚 好吧 并非所有资源都可能有效
So if a user did not submit the necessary information, we're just not going to let you make the resource.
因此 如果用户没有提交必要的信息 我们将不允许您创建资源
If I tell you that you have to have a Google Sheets URL and you just don't give me one, what am I supposed to query?
如果我告诉你必须有一个 Google Sheets URL 而你就是不给我 我应该查询什么？
I just can't do much.
我无能为力
And Java does the same.
Java 也是如此
If you have knowingly bad code, like you try to assign a string to an integer, it knows that it's wrong.
如果你有明知故犯的错误代码 比如你试图将一个字符串赋值给一个整数 它就知道这是错误的
If you pass in the wrong parameter type, it knows that it's wrong.
如果你传入错误的参数类型 它就知道这是错误的
And so the compiler will error at you.
所以编译器会向你报错
You can try lying to the compiler, casting things around, but then it just fails at runtime.
你可以尝试欺骗编译器 转换一些东西 但它会在运行时失败
And so this is specified in what's called a validation function.
这在所谓的验证函数中指定
And we actually include this in the resource configuration.
我们实际上将其包含在资源配置中
So that means that validation for a resource comes included, batteries included, out of the box.
这意味着资源的验证是包含在内的 开箱即用的
And so the idea is that without even knowing what a resource is, we can always call this validation function because we know that exists based on the interface that we have it.
所以想法是 即使不知道资源是什么 我们也可以始终调用此验证函数 因为我们知道它基于我们拥有的接口而存在
Great example is that any list can use the size method.
一个很好的例子是任何列表都可以使用 size 方法
It doesn't matter what sort of list you have.
你有什么样的清单都无所谓
They all have access to size by virtue of being a list.
由于它们都是列表 因此它们都可以访问 size
So the next idea that we want to implement is this thing called missing fields.
所以我们想要实现的下一个想法是这个叫做缺失字段的东西
So if a user puts in credentials, we don't want to just say, hey, you can't make the resource.
因此 如果用户输入凭据 我们不想只是说 嘿 你不能创建资源
We want to say what you're missing.
我们想说你错过了什么
If you didn't put in the Google Sheets URL, the user should see a message saying,
如果你没有输入 Google Sheets URL 用户应该会看到一条消息 说
hey, you forgot to put in a Google Sheets URL, so we can't make this resource for you.
嘿 你忘记输入 Google Sheets URL 了 所以我们无法为你创建这个资源
Or maybe they're missing other details, like the name of the resource, their login information.
或者他们可能缺少其他详细信息 例如资源的名称、他们的登录信息
So we want to go and tell them those details.
所以我们想去告诉他们这些细节
So my objective now is to add a way to track these missing fields and then incorporate validation for those fields.
所以我现在目标是添加一种方法来跟踪这些缺失的字段 然后将这些字段的验证合并进来
And that way, a user can be informed on what needs to change more than just telling them that, hey, it's not going to work.
这样一来 用户就可以被告知需要改变什么 而不仅仅是告诉他们 嘿 这行不通
So here's a question that we can answer.
所以这是一个我们可以回答的问题
How can we expand functionality to include this?
我们如何扩展功能以包含这一点？
And what would we need to change to implement missing fields into our system?
我们需要改变什么才能将缺失的字段实现到我们的系统中？
This is a question for you all, so if anyone wants to take a stab.
这是一个给你们大家的问题 所以如果有人想尝试一下
Yes.
是的
I'm sorry?
对不起？
You can have fallbacks.
你可以有后备
What do you mean by fallbacks?
你说的后备是什么意思？
Yes, you can.
是的 你可以
That is.
那是
That's actually a good point.
这实际上是一个很好的观点
Yeah, that's actually very true.
是的 这实际上非常正确
So you can have defaults.
所以你可以有默认值
If a user doesn't give you information, you can show something to them.
如果用户没有提供信息 你可以向他们展示一些东西
One thing is that for this particular scenario, sometimes we'll run into issues where we don't know what the default is.
有一件事是 对于这种特殊情况 有时我们会遇到我们不知道默认值是什么的问题
If you're telling me access to Google Sheets, what do I put as the default?
如果你告诉我可以访问 Google Sheets 我应该将什么作为默认值？
But you have a lot of different Google Sheets, right?
但是你有很多不同的 Google Sheets 对吧？
So you can't just have one for all of them.
所以你不能只为所有这些都有一个
You'd have one per different.
每个不同的都有一个
So how do I deal with this idea of telling the user that it's missing?
那么我如何处理告诉用户它丢失的这个想法？
You want to take a stab?
你想尝试一下吗？
Yes.
是的
AUDIENCE 2 Yeah.
观众 2 是的
My guess is you add to your interface a function you can call that will return a construct or something with one field.
我的猜测是 你在你的接口中添加了一个可以调用的函数 它将返回一个带有 1 个字段的结构或其他东西
Yeah, no, that's exactly right.
是的 不 那完全正确
That's actually exactly what I did.
这实际上就是我所做的
So the solution was we rethought validation as passing a missing fields test.
所以解决方案是我们重新思考验证作为通过缺失字段测试
And the missing fields test was that we would return basically a struct of what the missing fields are.
缺失字段测试是我们基本上会返回一个关于哪些字段缺失的结构
So I give you a list of missing fields.
所以我给你一个缺失字段的列表
And that way, you know what's not there.
这样 你就知道那里有什么没有
And then we rethink validation as being that the list of missing fields should be empty.
然后我们将验证重新思考为缺失字段列表应该为空
And this matters because if we didn't rethink it, then we have a validation function and we have a missing fields function.
这很重要 因为如果我们不重新思考它 那么我们就有一个验证函数和一个缺失字段函数
But they both might be out of sync.
但它们都可能不同步
What happens if you see a missing field, but it's validated?
如果你看到一个缺失的字段 但它已经过验证 会发生什么？
That doesn't make sense.
这说不通
Why am I being told that it's missing if I can make the resource?
如果我可以创建资源 为什么还要告诉我它丢失了？
Or vice versa.
反之亦然
What if there are no missing fields, but I have to validate it?
如果没有缺失的字段 但我必须验证它怎么办？
Then I feel like it's a bug and something is going wrong.
然后我觉得这是一个错误 出了问题
So we link the two together so we know that they're always going to be in sync.
所以我们将两者联系在一起 这样我们就知道它们总是同步的
And so that way, we can synchronize between them.
这样 我们就可以在它们之间进行同步
So the missing fields equals validation, and validation equals missing fields.
所以缺失的字段等于验证 验证等于缺失的字段
We can also upgrade the fields.
我们还可以升级字段
So let's say later on that I say that every port number should be a number and that you can't try to put in a string or characters or exclamation marks or anything.
假设稍后我说每个端口号都应该是一个数字 并且你不能尝试输入字符串或字符或感叹号或任何东西
I just change it one time for the port number for the general database, and it changes it for every single kind of database.
我只为通用数据库的端口号更改一次 它就为每一种数据库更改一次
And this matters.
这很重要
The company had like 30 kinds of databases.
该公司有大约 30 种数据库
So this one small change really saves time for what people are doing.
所以这个小小的改变真的为人们正在做的事情节省了时间
We update every single usage by upgrading this one field component.
我们通过升级这一个字段组件来更新每一个使用
An analogy here is that if I have some superclass and I change that, every single subclass that inherits from it gets the change functionality as well.
这里的一个类比是 如果我有一个超类并且我更改了它 那么每个继承自它的子类也会获得更改功能
So one last part that I want to talk about here was testing.
所以我想在这里谈的最后一部分是测试
And testing matters.
测试很重要
I know that no one probably really likes testing.
我知道可能没有人真正喜欢测试
Can I get a show of hands?
我可以举手示意吗？
Who here loves testing?
这里有谁喜欢测试？
Like, you just love writing tests?
比如 你只是喜欢编写测试？
Yeah, exactly.
是的 就是这样
It's not something that anyone really enjoys.
这不是任何人真正喜欢的东西
But it does matter, right?
但这确实很重要 对吧？
Because in the real world, we don't have an autograder.
因为在现实世界中 我们没有自动评分器
Even the autograder that you all use to test your projects, we on core staff have to write the test for.
即使你们都用来测试项目的自动评分器 我们核心人员也必须为其编写测试
So someone at the end of the day is writing tests in order to say that your code is correct.
所以最终总有人在编写测试 以便说你的代码是正确的
And so here, we're trying to figure out, would the right missing fields be displayed?
所以在这里 我们正在尝试弄清楚 是否会显示正确的缺失字段？
And this is really important.
这真的很重要
Imagine you're a customer paying millions of dollars to this company.
想象一下 你是一位向这家公司支付数百万美元的客户
You log on, and there's some intern's work who you're going into, and you're trying to make a resource, and it's not letting you make it, but it's showing you that you have no missing fields, and you're really confused.
你登录 有一些实习生的工作你要去做 你试图创建一个资源 它不让你创建 但它向你显示你没有缺失的字段 你真的很困惑
If any customer quits that, I get fired.
如果任何客户退出 我就会被解雇
So it matters that you don't let these kinds of things slip into production.
所以重要的是不要让这些事情进入生产环境
So to do that, I built a utility that tested every possible combination of inputs and outputs, but I designed it for that general database.
为此 我构建了一个实用程序 可以测试输入和输出的每种可能组合 但我将其设计用于通用数据库
So the idea of patterning the resource, if every resource is going to follow that, then I've just hit 30 resources in testing just with one thing.
所以对资源进行模式化的想法 如果每个资源都将遵循该模式 那么我只需测试一件事就可以测试 30 个资源
And so we can be really thorough.
这样我们就可以非常彻底
We can test every single little case.
我们可以测试每一个小案例
There was even some cases where we actually built mock resources.
有些情况下我们甚至构建了模拟资源
We had a sample database that you could query from, and we validated that you could query from it correctly.
我们有一个示例数据库 你可以从中查询 并且我们验证了你是否可以正确地从中查询
And in other resources, like Elasticsearch, like Databricks, we had select test cases that we thought were most important to users, and then we manually wrote those.
在其他资源中 如 Elasticsearch、Databricks 我们选择了我们认为对用户最重要的测试用例 然后我们手动编写了这些用例
And we included this all as one big testing suite, so any time anyone made any change,
我们将所有这些都包含在一个大型测试套件中 所以任何人在任何时候进行任何更改
So even if you were changing something totally unrelated to this, maybe you were changing the logo on some part of the documentation screen,
即使你更改的是与之完全无关的内容 也许你正在更改文档屏幕某个部分的logo
it still runs these tests, just in case, like we said all the way at the beginning, that functionality change impacts every single other part of the functionality.
它仍然会运行这些测试 以防万一 就像我们在一开始说的 功能更改会影响到其他所有功能
Everything touches everything, and so you make sure that it works.
一切都相互关联 所以你要确保它能正常工作
So this pattern is really powerful.
所以这种模式非常强大
If we update the utility once, it updates everywhere.
如果我们更新一次实用程序 它就会更新到所有地方
And that way, we also can future-proof our code to the best of our ability.
这样 我们还可以尽最大努力使我们的代码面向未来
By making things overlap, we can update that one usage of the resource, and it replicates everywhere.
通过使事物重叠 我们可以更新资源的一种用法 它会复制到所有地方
OK, so that marks the end of that particular project.
好的 这就标志着那个特定项目的结束了
That project, I know it sounds a little dry.
我知道这个项目听起来有点枯燥
But it's quite interesting when you think about it, right?
但仔细想想 它还是很有趣的 对吧？
This idea of querying and all the difficulties that come with it.
关于查询的想法 以及随之而来的所有困难
This next one has to do with Git commits.
下一个项目与 Git 提交有关
And it's actually going to apply graphs and breadth-first search and a lot of other concepts that you all just learned about.
它实际上将应用图、广度优先搜索和许多其他你们刚学到的概念
And so the idea of this one is to motivate this idea that what you're learning about actually is useful and does matter in the real world.
所以这个项目的想法是为了激发这样一个想法：你正在学习的东西实际上是有用的 并且在现实世界中确实很重要
So I'm going to start out with some motivation for the problem.
所以我将从这个问题的一些动机开始
So let's say I'm building some project.
假设我正在构建某个项目
And I want to see what versions of that project contain some change.
我想看看那个项目的哪些版本包含了某些更改
So I want to compare metrics.
所以我想比较指标
Let's say I want to compare adoption.
假设我想比较采用率
How many users are using it?
有多少用户在使用它？
And I want to see, compared to other things, how is our project doing?
我想看看 与其他项目相比 我们的项目进展如何？
Maybe there's some metric we're looking at.
也许我们正在关注某个指标
Maybe there's some change that we need to validate or make sure that is quality assurance tested.
也许我们需要验证或确保进行质量保证测试的某个更改
So the problem is that we don't allow every single update to go to your phone.
问题是 我们不允许每一个更新都发送到你的手机上
So if you think about your phone, your phone probably gets an update like what?
如果你想想你的手机 你的手机可能多久更新一次？
Like once every few months.
比如每隔几个月更新一次
Maybe you update it once a year.
也许你一年更新一次
Maybe you update for some small security issue every once in a while.
也许你偶尔会为一些小的安全问题更新
But the idea is that we only release new versions in a cycle.
但我们的想法是 我们只在一个周期内发布新版本
And we have very minor changes in between.
并且我们在两者之间进行非常小的更改
But every single year, we know Apple is going to release a new version of iOS, macOS, iPadOS, all these various things.
但每年 我们都知道 Apple 会发布新版本的 iOS、macOS、iPadOS 等各种版本
Think about grade scope.
想想 GradeScope(全局作用域)
Grade scope does the same.
GradeScope 也是一样
It only takes a small number of submissions.
它只接受少量的提交
You might be working on more changes locally.
你可能在本地进行更多的更改
You might be making more commits.
你可能在进行更多的提交
But you can't be pushing every single one of those.
但你不能推送每一个
So grade scope, in that case, is enforcing it, whereas in the first example, you were enforcing it on Apple and Google.
所以在这种情况下 GradeScope 在强制执行它 而在第一个例子中 你是在 Apple 和 Google 上强制执行它
And so the key idea is that they don't release every single time you make a new commit internally.
所以关键的想法是 他们不会在你每次在内部进行新的提交时都发布
So if a developer pushes some code, even if it goes into their main code base, you don't just give it out to all of the users.
所以如果一个开发者推送了一些代码 即使它进入了他们的主代码库 你也不会把它直接分发给所有用户
So if you look over here, even if you're like, oh, automatically download iOS updates and prepare for installation, it doesn't happen all the time.
所以如果你看看这里 即使你像“自动下载 iOS 更新并准备安装”一样 它也不会一直发生
So that's the initial setup for the problem.
这就是这个问题的初始设置
Now let's say some constraints on how we're doing this.
现在让我们说一些关于我们如何做这件事的限制
So for simplicity, let's just treat every change like a Git commit.
为了简单起见 让我们把每一次更改都视为一次 Git 提交
So commits are snapshots of your code at a moment in time.
所以提交是你代码在某个时间点的快照
And so we can use the commits to store the differences in your code as you make changes.
因此 我们可以使用提交来存储你在进行更改时代码中的差异
So this is the same commit that you push whenever you finish a lab, when you finish a project.
所以这是你在完成实验、完成项目时推送的相同提交
You're pushing it to your GitHub repository and then synchronizing with GitHub.
你正在将其推送到你的 GitHub 存储库 然后与 GitHub 同步
Versions refer to the most recent Git commits on a given branch.
版本是指给定分支上最新的 Git 提交
Let's say you also have easy access to all the git commits, so we don't have to worry about getting access to them.
假设你还可以轻松访问所有 git 提交 所以我们不必担心如何访问它们
We can load them onto your computer in a reasonable amount of time.
我们可以在合理的时间内将它们加载到你的计算机上
Let's say that we have a lot of commits.
假设我们有很多提交
So you can't just store for a given deployment, for a given release, every single commit that's included in it.
所以你不能仅仅为了一个给定的部署 一个给定的版本 就存储其中包含的每一个提交
Let's say that that's infeasible for now.
假设现在这是不可行的
And let's also say that once a change is made, we don't undo or modify that change.
我们还假设 一旦进行了更改 我们就不会撤消或修改该更改
So in reality, someone might come along and change that part of the code later on.
所以在现实中 可能会有人来稍后更改代码的那部分
But we can use something called git blame,
但我们可以使用一个名为 git blame 的东西
which tells us what GitHub username went in and changed that line of code in the future, if we actually wanted to implement this and get around that.
它告诉我们将来哪个 GitHub 用户名进入并更改了那行代码 如果我们真的想实现它并解决这个问题的话
The last and really important assumption that we have to make for
最后一个也是非常重要的假设 我们必须做出这个假设
why this is even a problem at all is that we assume that manually splitting the commits for inclusion,
我们假设手动拆分提交以决定哪些提交应该包含在发布版本中是非常困难的 也就是说
so figuring out is one commit in the release, is one commit not in the release, like it came after that version, is really hard.
判断一个提交是否应该包含在发布版本中 比如是否来自于该版本之后的提交 这是一件很困难的事情
And when I say really hard, it's not like we have dozens of commits, or when you all are working on projects, probably singles of commits, like maybe three.
当我说“真的很难”时 并不是说我们有几十个提交 或者当你们都在做项目时 可能只有几个提交 比如三个
We have millions or billions of commits.
我们有数百万或数十亿个提交
And these are a lot.
这些太多了
There's no way that anybody could look at these.
任何人都不可能查看这些
Even if you had a team of people, they're probably still not going to be able to look at it.
即使你有一个团队 他们可能仍然无法查看它
So we basically kind of have to have some sort of code-based solution.
所以我们基本上必须有某种基于代码的解决方案
Now we're going to introduce an idea that might be interesting, is thinking about Git as a graph.
现在我们将介绍一个可能很有趣的想法 就是将 Git 视为一个图
And so maybe you saw this earlier in the Git lab, where we drew out this graph idea.
也许你在之前的 Git 实验中看到过这个 我们画出了这个图的想法
But the idea is that going from the left to the right, we have this time of commit.
但想法是 从左到右 我们有这个提交时间
So the commits that are more on the right come after.
所以更靠右的提交是在之后进行的
Every single commit has a parent of some sort, potentially two if it is a merge commit.
每个提交都有某种父级 如果是合并提交 则可能有两个
So each vertex inside of our graph is a commit.
所以我们图中的每个顶点都是一个提交
And then each edge is directed.
然后每条边都是有向的
From the commit to its parent.
从提交到其父级
So these are unweighted edges, because we aren't assigning any weight between a commit and its parent.
所以这些是未加权的边 因为我们没有在提交与其父级之间分配任何权重
If you were just the parent, there is no more parent or less parent than anyone else.
如果你只是父级 那么没有比其他任何人更多或更少的父级
And commits store their parents.
并且提交存储它们的父级
Since upon creation, a commit only knows its parents, but it does not know who's going to come from it in the future as children.
因为在创建时 提交只知道它的父级 但它不知道将来谁会作为子级来自它
So if I'm making f, I don't know what other commits are going to descend from f in the future, but I know that f is a merge commit between e and c.
所以如果我正在制作 F 我不知道将来还有什么其他提交会从 F 中衍生出来 但我知道 F 是 E 和 C 之间的合并提交
Now let's take this as an example.
现在让我们以这个为例
And now let's factor in what we said at the very beginning, that not every single commit is deployed to the user.
现在让我们考虑一下我们在一开始所说的 并不是每个提交都部署给用户
Let's say that the green commits are deployed commits.
假设绿色的提交是已部署的提交
And I make some change in commit C. And I ask this question, which releases contain my change?
我在提交 C 中做了一些更改 我问这个问题 哪些版本包含我的更改？
Can anyone help me out in figuring which of the green commits here contain the change in C?
谁能帮我弄清楚这里的哪些绿色提交包含了 C 中的更改？
I promise you, there is no trick to this question.
我向你保证 这个问题没有技巧
Anyone want to take a stab?
有人想尝试一下吗？
Yes.
是的
D, E, F, G. You're very close.
D、E、F、G 你很接近了
So E and F are both not deployed commits, because they're not green commits.
所以 E 和 F 都不是已部署的提交 因为它们不是绿色的提交
So we ignore them.
所以我们忽略它们
It's D and G, and it's also C, because C itself is a deployed commit.
是 D 和 G 也是 C 因为 C 本身就是一个已部署的提交
But you had the right idea.
但你的想法是对的
How did you figure out that it was those four commits to look at?
你是如何确定要查看这四个提交的？
Exactly.
没错
So the algorithm was that we started at C. We saw who was descended from it, which commits had C as its parent.
所以算法是我们从 C 开始 我们看到了谁是它的后代 哪些提交以 C 作为其父级
And then we worked our way backwards.
然后我们一路往回走
And so we did a search from C. We found D, E, F, and G. Exactly right.
所以我们从C开始搜索 找到了D、E、F和G 完全正确
So if you want to follow that out, we started from C. We go backwards to D and F.
顺着这条线 我们从C开始 回溯到D和F 然后碰到E和G
Then we go and hit E and G. So if I ask you which deployed commits, it's just C, D, and G, because we're trying to see which ones are green.
所以如果我问你哪些提交被部署了 答案是C、D和G 因为我们想看看哪些是绿色的
Now let's see an approach to solving this question.
现在让我们看看解决这个问题的方法
So maybe there's two approaches.
可能会有两种方法
We'll start with the one that we just talked about.
我们先从刚才讨论的那个开始
We work backwards.
我们向前回溯
We look at commits storing parents.
我们查看存储父节点的提交
And Git is designed to tell us parents of commits through Git logs.
Git 的设计就是通过 `Git logs` 告诉我们提交的父节点
So maybe this is a little bit challenging to think about.
所以这可能有点难思考
But this is what we did previously.
但这就是我们之前做的事情
So this is what we just did.
这就是我们刚刚做的
This is how it would work.
这就是它的工作原理
Another option is to work in the direction that Git tells us.
另一个选择是按照 Git 告诉我们的方向工作
Maybe I take a look at commits and I see who the parent of that commit is instead of trying to figure out who the child of that commit is.
也许我会查看提交 看看那个提交的父节点是谁 而不是试图找出那个提交的子节点是谁
Now, this is a little annoying because now we have to grab every single ending commit, all the commits on the right-hand side, and then work our way left
现在 这有点烦人 因为我们必须抓住每一个结束提交 也就是右侧的所有提交 然后向左移动
until we hit the change that we're looking for at commit C. And if we don't hit the change, we can only terminate once we work backwards and we have to check timestamps.
直到我们找到我们在提交 C 处寻找的更改 如果我们没有找到更改 我们只能在回溯到最后并检查时间戳后才能终止
And it becomes a little annoying because we don't want to go all the way back to the very first commit, but we do need to stop eventually.
这有点烦人 因为我们不想一直回到最初的提交 但我们确实需要最终停下来
Here's an example of what that means.
这里有一个例子来说明这意味着什么
I start over here on the right-hand side, and I push all the way until I stop at C. And then once I stop at C, then I know, have I hit anybody that has C as its parent?
我从右侧开始 一直推到 C 停止 一旦我在 C 停止 我就知道了 我有没有碰到过任何以 C 为父节点？
Well, the answer is yes.
嗯 答案是肯定的
I start at H. H takes us to B, which is before C. So I know that B can't contain the change in C. It's not possible to contain a change that's coming in the future.
我从 H 开始 H 把我们带到 B B 在 C 之前 所以我知道 B 不能包含 C 中的更改 包含未来才会出现的更改是不可能的
Then I hit G. G goes backward to E to D. And then I realize that G and D are both descended from C. So that works.
然后我碰到 G G 向后到 E 到 D 然后我意识到 G 和 D 都是 C 的后代 所以这行得通
Then I hit F. F is OK, but F isn't a deployed commit.
然后我碰到 F F 没问题 但 F 不是一个已部署的提交
But I keep going.
但我继续前进
I see the E, D, C route and the C route.
我看到了 E、D、C 路线和 C 路线
I do the same for E. I do the same for D. That should feel a lot more complicated.
我对 E 也做同样的处理 对 D 也做同样的处理 这应该会让人觉得复杂得多
Something should feel weird about that solution compared to the first one.
与第一个解决方案相比 这个解决方案应该会让你觉得有些奇怪
You should innately just be like, wait, that seems like a very awkward way of doing this.
你应该本能地觉得 等等 这似乎是一种非常笨拙的做事方式
And you're actually right.
你说的没错
The idea here is that
这里的想法是
If we had, let's say, even more branches, even more commits going all over the place, this becomes really complicated, really challenging, and really annoying to deal with.
如果我们有 比如说 更多的分支 更多的提交到处都是 这就会变得非常复杂 非常具有挑战性 而且非常令人讨厌
Imagine trying to fix a bug with this method of doing it.
想象一下 用这种方法来修复一个 bug
So perhaps what we can do is we can deal with that earlier challenging part that I talked about,
所以也许我们可以做的是 我们可以处理我之前谈到的那个更具挑战性的部分
which is that Git is designed to tell us who the parent is, not the child is, because you can't tell the future.
那就是 Git 的设计目的是告诉我们谁是父节点 而不是子节点 因为你无法预测未来
And what we do is we normally think about Git in a commit-parent relationship.
我们通常认为 Git 是一种提交-父节点关系
So here's an example of a Git log that I did last semester when I QA'd Project 1C.
所以这里有一个 Git 日志的例子 是我上学期在做 Project 1C 的 QA 时做的
So you see that you have on the left-hand side the commit of the actual commit, and on the right-hand side is the commit ID of your parents.
所以你可以看到 在左侧是实际提交的提交 在右侧是你父节点的提交 ID
But what if we reversed it?
但如果我们把它颠倒过来呢？
So what if I created some mapping, and I mapped every single parent to the commit?
所以 如果我创建一些映射 并将每个父节点都映射到提交上会怎样？
So I reversed the order of all the edges.
所以我把所有边的顺序都颠倒了
And then we do what was mentioned earlier, and we do a BFS from that commit forward in time to find deployments that contain it.
然后我们做前面提到的 我们从那个提交开始向前进行 BFS 以找到包含它的部署
So it sounds a little weird, but we're not trying to find children that don't exist.
所以这听起来有点奇怪 但我们并不是想找到不存在的子节点
We're just trying to say, if you already do exist, just flip the ordering around.
我们只是想说 如果你已经存在 那就把顺序颠倒一下
And we'll use an adjacency list because technically for a commit, you can just store instance variables of how the commits.
我们将使用一个邻接表 因为从技术上讲 对于一个提交 你只需要存储提交的实例变量
You could just store commit one parent and potentially a merge commit, a second parent.
你只需要存储提交的一个父节点 以及可能的一个合并提交 一个第二个父节点
But if you have children, well, you could have infinite children.
但如果你有孩子 那么你可能有无数个孩子
And so we generalize that idea with just one big list, and we store everybody in that.
所以我们用一个大的列表来概括这个想法 我们将每个人都存储在其中
Now let's talk about the solution very formally, just one slide explaining how it works.
现在让我们非常正式地讨论一下解决方案 只需一张幻灯片来解释它是如何工作的
So we can include a lot more optimizations and things like that.
所以我们可以包含更多的优化和类似的东西
But here's the gist of it.
但这就是要点
The very first part is we build this Git commit graph.
第一部分是我们构建这个 Git 提交图
We store mappings from commits to their children.
我们将提交映射到它们的子节点
And then we generate a set of the deployed commits.
然后我们生成一组已部署的提交
This is separate from the graph.
这与图是分开的
Think about this as which nodes are marked in green.
把它想象成哪些节点被标记为绿色
Why might I want to use a set for this instead of a list?
为什么我可能想为此使用集合而不是列表？
Yes?
有吗？
No duplicates, exactly, right?
没有重复 完全正确
Because we don't care about the duplicateness and also the runtime, right?
因为我们不关心重复性 也不关心运行时间 对吧？
Because we don't care about the ordering of the list, right?
因为我们不关心列表的顺序 对吧？
Lists are ordered collections, ordered sequences.
列表是有序集合 有序序列
And we don't actually care that some commit is earlier via timestamps compared to a later one later in the list.
我们实际上并不关心某个提交通过时间戳与列表中后面的提交相比更早
So a set just gives us access to this easy runtime of just constant time amortized if we just use a hash set.
所以一个集合只是让我们能够轻松地以常数时间摊销的方式访问 如果我们只使用一个哈希集合的话
And then we do a BFS.
然后我们进行 BFS
We look at the input commit, and then we check if commits traversed are in the deployed commits.
我们查看输入提交 然后检查遍历的提交是否在已部署的提交中
And the nice thing is that we can actually do step 3 independent of step 1 and 2.
好处是我们可以独立于步骤 1 和 2 来执行步骤 3
Because if I had multiple input commits, maybe I have multiple people coming and asking, hey, which versions are included or have my change in them?
因为如果我有多个输入提交 也许会有多个人来问 嘿 哪些版本包含了我的更改或者有我的更改？
Well, they just give me all of their commits, all of their changes at once, and I can compute it.
好吧 他们只是把他们所有的提交 他们所有的更改一次性给我 我就可以计算出来
via 3 over and over.
通过一遍又一遍地执行步骤 3
So we can do 1 and 2, and then we can run 3 over as many times as needed.
所以我们可以做步骤 1 和 2 然后我们可以根据需要多次运行步骤 3
Because in practice, step 1 is the one that takes the longest, just due to the nature of how loading things into your random access memory works.
因为在实践中 步骤 1 是花费时间最长的 这只是由于将东西加载到随机存取存储器的工作原理所致
But it allows us to still work a lot faster.
但它仍然让我们能够更快地工作
This whole process, maximal time will be roughly on the order of minutes, high seconds.
整个过程 最大时间大约在分钟级 高秒级
But compared to doing it manually, which was basically impossible for millions of commits, it seems a lot better.
但与手动操作相比 手动操作对于数百万次提交来说基本上是不可能的 这似乎要好得多
In some ways, it was obvious and modular.
在某种程度上 它是显而易见的和模块化的
I didn't have to explain to you what the algorithm was.
我不需要向你解释算法是什么
Just by seeing a visual diagram, you were able to get some intuition on how to approach the problem.
只要看到一个可视化的图表 你就能对如何处理这个问题有一些直觉
Now, this wasn't the entire problem.
现在 这不是问题的全部
It was a subproblem.
这是一个子问题
But this was the main chunk of that problem.
但这是那个问题的主要部分
So without getting into the optimizations and details, you were able to solve a lot of it.
所以 在不深入了解优化和细节的情况下 你已经能够解决很多问题了
Now let's wrap up real quick.
现在让我们快速总结一下
Let me see how we're doing on time.
让我看看我们时间安排得怎么样
Oh, we're at time.
哦 到时间了
I'll get this really fast.
我会很快说完的
So we have a couple of takeaways.
所以我们有几点收获
First takeaway is I want you all to feel like 61B is useful.
第一个收获是 我希望你们都觉得 61B 是有用的
I know sometimes it feels like it's not, but it is actually quite applicable.
我知道有时候感觉它没什么用 但它实际上是相当适用的
You're able to solve a lot of problems via that.
你能够通过它解决很多问题
Second is that good code is more than just working code.
第二点是 好的代码不仅仅是能工作的代码
We want to make the most optimizations we can.
我们希望尽可能地进行优化
Code complexity scales with functionality.
代码的复杂性与功能成正比
You want to practice good design principles in your classes.
你希望在你的类中实践良好的设计原则
It's very important that you test your code.
测试你的代码非常重要
And the real world is going to give you a lot of ambiguous problems.
现实世界会给你很多模棱两可的问题
It's your job to figure out what those constraints are.
你的工作是找出这些限制是什么
And then finally, if this sounds interesting to you, check out engineering blogs.
最后 如果这听起来很有趣 那就去看看工程博客